VIGNAN VENNAMPALLY

Boston, MA 02215 | vennampally.v@northeastern.edu | 8574539100 | LinkedIn | GitHub

SUMMARY

Data Scientist with 2 years of industry experience on analyzing Complex Datasets & delivering action-oriented results to complex business problems. Proficient in Predictive Modeling, Data Mining, Statistical Modeling. Seeking opportunities as a Data Scientist to fully utilize analytical & story-telling skills.

EDUCATION

Northeastern University, Boston, USA

May 2023

Master's in Data Analytics Engineering, (GPA: 4/4)

Indian Institute of Information Technology, Jabalpur, India

July 2020

Bachelors in Electronics and Communication Engineering, (GPA: 7.6/10)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python (Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-learn, SciPy, Seaborn, Matplotlib, TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch), R, SQL, C **Data Engineering & Databases:** ETL, Hadoop, Apache Spark, MySQL, MongoDB

Tools & Technologies: Azure, AWS, Kubernetes, Docker, Linux OS, Power BI, Tableau

Modeling: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, NLP, Statistical Modeling, Hypothesis Testing, A/B testing

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Science Co-op | Alexion AstraZeneca Rare Disease, Boston, MA

Jun 2022 - Present

- Developed business rules and designed Predictive modeling road map to increase the commercial use of KOSELUGO
- Analyzed 2 billion IQVIA LAAD data to find complex patterns among the patients diagnosed with NF1
- Performed extensive Exploratory Data Analysis on Claims & Prescription data to answer business questions
- Developed efficient SQL alerts to find out the targeted patients and HCPs to commercialize the usage of Koselugo

Software Engineer, Data Science Application | Ericsson India Global Services, Bangalore, India Aug 2020 - Aug 2021

- Engineered the configuration of <u>Dataiku DSS</u> in Production, Sandbox, POC environments that unify business, Data & IT teams to centralize AI tasks from data to impact
- Developed efficient Linux bash scripts and macros in Python to automate the server and log management,
 Memory Management tasks that boosted the server performance by 20%
- Worked on 10+ Machine Learning use case projects starting from data collection to Model deployment
- Resolved 100+ production issues of the application that efficiently increased the bug velocity

Data Science Intern | IIT Kanpur, India

May 2019 - Nov 2019

- Conducted Extensive Data Extraction from MySQL, MongoDB Databases through efficient SQL queries
- Built an ML model to predict the dropout rates from MOOC courses. Improved the model performance to 94.5% and increased the retention rate of customers by 25%
- Enhanced and Redesigned the Analytical Interface of mooKIT Platform using Python framework (Plotly Dash), Power BI and Tableau to gain statistical insights of 400 course participants

NLP Research Assistant | Northeastern University, Boston, MA

Jan 2022 - Apr 2022

- Performed Data Extraction of different airline tweets using <u>Twint</u> (Twitter Scraping Tool) to understand the consumer's voice
- Implemented NLP techniques like Stemming, Lemmatization and Vectorization to process the data
- Analyzed the sentiment of tweets using <u>TextBlob</u> to categorize them as positive, negative, and neutral
- Data Visualization and Exploration were performed in Tableau to find out hidden facts and insights

Deep Learning Research Assistant | Augmented Cognition Lab, Portland, Maine

May 2022 - Jul 2022

- Implemented Haar Cascade (Viola Jones) method which utilizes integral Image, AdaBoost, Attentional Cascade technique to track & analyze infant breathing and sleeping rates
- Developed Multi-cascade deep learning neural networks (MTCNN's) which implements three CNN's (P-Net, R-Net, O-Net) & concepts of Bounding boxes, NMS (Non Maximum Suppression) to detect Infants mouth region

PROJECTS

University - Student - Financial Enterprise Model

 Designed a database for the University Student Bank loan ecosystem which helps Students and Banks in making better decisions. Modeled ER, EER, UML and Relation Data Models for the database using concepts of Normalization, Specialization, Aggregation and Categorization.